Guide to the Geoffrey Wells (Geoffrey West) Papers 1928-1942
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Geoffrey Wells (Geoffrey West) Papers
1928-1942
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 745
West, Geoffrey, 1900-
.25 Linear Feet of Shelf Space 1 box
Geoffrey Wells, who wrote under the name Geoffrey West, was an English novelist, literary critic and biographer. The collection consists of correspondence from Geoffrey Wells to the American essayist, critic, and naturalist Henry Chester Tracy. Wells wrote on a variety of subjects in these letters, but often focused on literary subjects.
Geoffrey Wells, who wrote under the name Geoffrey West, was an English novelist, literary critic and biographer. His best-known work, H.G. Wells: Sketch for a Portrait, was published in 1930.
The collection consists of correspondence from Geoffrey Wells to the American essayist, critic, and naturalist Henry Chester Tracy. Wells wrote on a variety of subjects in these letters, but often focused on literary subjects. The correspondence begins in 1927 with a letter to Tracy as part of his research for his biography of Annie Besant; later letters mention his other writing projects, and Tracy's comments on them, and Wells's responses to many of Tracy's writings. Other topics include the review and promotion of Tracy's books in England, and matters concerning many of their acquaintances in literary and publishing circles, including Middleton Murry, Leonard Woolf, Desmond McCarthy, A.R. Orage, Stanley Unwin, Christopher and F. V. Morley, and Fredric Warburg. He also discussed politics and the impending world war, and, occasionally, personal matters.
The items are arranged in a single chronological sequence.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was purchased in 1984 from Serendipity Books.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
West, Geoffrey, 1900- -- Correspondence.; Tracy, Henry Chester, 1876- -- Correspondence.
Authors, English -- 20th century -- Archives.; Publishers and publishing -- England.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.
Literature; Publishers and Publishing
- Correspondence from Wells to Henry Chester Tracy
  - 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1931 (includes photograph of Wells) (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1932 and undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administrative file